<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">A&amp;A</string>
    <string name="title_section1">Home</string>
    <string name="title_section2">Pastor Biography</string>
    <string name="title_section3">Saved From What</string>
    <string name="title_section4">Statement of Faith</string>
    <string name="title_section5">Photo Gallery</string>
    <string name="title_section6">Events Calendar</string>
    <string name="title_section7">Audio/Video</string>
    <string name="title_section8">Service Times</string>
    <string name="title_section9">Contact Info</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="action_example">Example action</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="header_1">Dear Friend,</string>
    <string name="paragraph_1">I would like to welcome
    you to the website of Provisions for the Redeemed
    Christian Center (aka Vernessa Walker Ministries).
    I’m so glad you decided to visit. I’m so excited about
    the opportunity to charge the atmosphere with the word of God.
    If you are looking for a unique place to increase your knowledge
    in God’s word and find your place in God’s plan, then prayerfully
    consider this church a place to call home.</string>
    <string name="header_2">Church Vision</string>
    <string name="paragraph_2">The vision of Provisions
        for the Redeemed Christian Center (aka Vernessa Walker Ministries)
        is to teach the Word of God to the extent that all who hear will see
        and experience change in their lives. Changes to include healing,
        deliverance, prosperity, strength and all that God has offer.
        To teach God’s people how to tap into the spiritual realm of
        whom God is and why we worship him.</string>
    <string name="header_3">Pastor Vernessa F. Walker</string>
    <string name="paragraph_3">Pastor Walker is the founder of Provisions for the Redeemed Christian
        Center aka Vernessa Walker Ministries.
        She is the author of the book, ”It’s Time To Claim Your Promise”. She has hosted her own
        television and radio programs called Provisions for the Redeemed.
        She was born again and baptized at the age twelve at Big Indian Creek Primitive Baptist Church.
        Under the leadership of Elder Michael Hartwell in July 1988 she preached her first sermon.
        While there she held a position of Associate Minister, Sunday School teacher, Youth Advisor
        and participated in Prison Ministry. She implemented Children’s Church for Indian Creek as
        well as other sister churches. She is the seventh of eight children. She was born to Johnie
        Walker and Ida Mae Pride Walker. She attended the University of Alabama in Huntsville and
        Athens State College. She has a Bachelor’s of Science degree in Business Administration with
        a minor in Procurement and Acqusition Management. She also has a Master’s Degree in Theology.</string>
    <string name="header_4">Saved From What</string>
    <string name="paragraph_4">Saved For What?

SALVATION:
NOT WHAT WE ARE SAVED FROM BUT WHAT WE ARE SAVED TO ….

Author Vernessa Walker

All scriptures are taken from the King James Version of the Bible unless otherwise stated.

Understanding the glory of the Lord. Glory means garment, mantle, robe or covering. It describes the glory use in connection to man and God. The covering is God himself on us. Like the spirit hovering over the face of the water is the Holy Spirit presence on the earth. God’s glory in the Old Testament was not given to the people. It was not place on the inside of the people. However, the glory in New Testament was given to the people. It was placed on the inside of the people. Glory in the Old Testament was also used to describe one’s wealth. In both the Old and New Testament the glory was also used to describe a work or manifestation of the Lord. What we want to look at today is the glory of God in relationship to our salvation.

Original intent for His Glory. Gen. 1:1 In the beginning God created …
Gen. 1:26 And God said, Let us make man in our image, and after our likeness …
Gen. 1:27 So God created man in his own image, in the image of God created he him; male and female created he them.

Everyone is created in the image of God. It was God’s original intent that we look like them, talk like them and act like them. When I say them I mean the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit. At that point, our creation, our likeness to them was that the glory was our covering.

Although God breathed into man the breath of life – he did not put his glory in him. He put his glory on him. It was a covering. When Adam and Eve looked at each other what they saw was the glory of God. It was this likeness of God they saw. When God looked at them it was his likeness he saw.

When man fell from the grace of God it was this glory that was lifted. Adam and Eve didn’t feel anything flow out of them, their eyes were opened. In other words, the covers were removed from their eyes. The glory of God was lifted and they were no longer covered in his glory.

The glory of God, which did not allow them to see evil, which did not allow them to see themselves naked – that glory – that covering -, was removed.

God never intended for man to be without his glory. His original intent was that we always be covered in his glory.

The circle of glory and the crowning of man. The span of time between the Bible’s first and second verses, earth lay beneath water in contrast to the glorious perfection of the rest of creation.
Here we see the Holy Spirit moving upon the dark spots.

Gen 1:2 … And the Spirit of God moved upon the face of the waters.
Gen 1:1-2 NLT In the beginning God created the heavens and the earth. The earth was empty, a formless mass cloaked in darkness. And Spirit of God was hovering over its surface.
From here we see God’s first glorious words and there fulfillment.
Gen 1:3 And God said, “Let there be light:” and there was light.
God was not commanding the sun and the moon to become. They didn’t come forth until the fourth day. God was talking about the Light of Himself. In essence, this include: God returning Light and Life to the earth. He removed his Presence but know he will work there again. In God’s work we see he established a new order of thing. He separated the waters. He called forth the seed that was in the earth; he did not created new plant life (vv. 11, 12). In other words, he called forth that which already existed. He set the sun, the moon and the stars into place. He created new animal life (vv. 20, 21).
His work progressed in divisions. He called: the first day… The second day… The third day… the fourth day… The fifth day… And then the sixth day! The most astonishing day of all! The words in Gen 1: 26 took on a new tone. God was about to create man and the tone began to change. Previously he had called forth the new order of things and now he was about to roll up his sleeves. The most important effort of creation was about to take place, the creation of man.

Gen 1:26 And God said, Let us make man in our image, and after our likeness; and let them have dominion over the fish of the sea, and over the fowl of the air, and over the cattle, and over all the earth, and over every creeping thing that creepeth upon the earth.

This very act caused a stir in heaven. The very minute God mentioned man and creation a rumbling started in heaven. Angelic questions must have resounded in response to the startling news.
What is man? What is man? One angel even dared to ask God, the Creator in Psalm 8. Hebrews 2:5-7 tells us that it was and angel that ask the question. What is man?

Psalm 8:3-6 When I consider thy heavens the work of thy fingers, the moon and the stars, which thou hast ordained; What is man, that thou art mindful of him? And the son of man, that thou visitest him? For thou hast made him a little lower than the angels (Elohim), and hast crowned him with glory and honour. Thou madest him to have dominion over the works of thy hands; thou hast put all things under his feet.

This angel had watched the wonders of the work of God in creation. So he began by complimenting the Creator. Then he asked the big question. What is man, that thou are mindful of him? What is he that you have placed him on your mind? And the son of man, that thou visitest him? This angel is thinking here is one that God visits in the garden. For thou hast made him a little lower than the angles (Elohim)…

In the book of Hebrews the word angels is defined Elohim. Elohim is the plural word for God. It shows God the Father, God the Son, and God the Holy Spirit. Since the beginning of time the angels had known this order: The Trinity – Godhead, archangels, and angels. Now there is a new order in creation. Man is ranked just under the Godhead; the angels didn’t even know the position was open.

For thou hast made him a little lower than the angels (Elohim), and hast crowned him with glory and honour. God crowned man! He didn’t get Gabriel or Michael to go down and crown man with his glory. With all of his Majesty, God himself arose from his throne and came down and crowned man. This wasn’t a crown of gold or diamonds it was a crown of glory, His glory. It was a covering that consumed man’s entire body.

By this crowning God fixed forever the place of man in his heart and in his plans. God’s original intent was the crowning of man with his glory. The crown was made of the most valuable substance in all creation.
Thou… hast crown him with glory and honour.

The crown was made of glory! God’s glory! The “Glory” which may seem abstract to some, is the highest heavenly reality. The Glory of God is God’s presence manifested. The glory of God is God Himself. God’s glory sat upon man as his crown and clothed him as his covering. It fitted man for the fellowship he enjoyed with his creator as they walked in the cool of the garden. It was this that the angel could not understand. How could God care so much for man that he would put everything under his feet to have dominion?

Can you imagine? Satan was thrown out of heaven for wanting dominion over something, anything and here comes man. One whom God has place such trust in and given him dominion to rule over the works of His hands and put all things up under his feet. And the heart stopper – God crowns him (man) with His Glory. To satan – this was not a pretty picture it was a nightmare.

The fall of man. God’s word had gone forth; Man would have dominion over the works of his hands. Satan challenged it. If he could stop God’s word from coming to pass, he could defeat God. His tactics were simple. He tempted the will of man. Man yielded and turned his will crosswise to the will of God. It is here that we see the results of the fall of man.

Gen 2:25 And they were both naked, the man and his wife, and were not ashamed.
Gen. 3:7-11 And the eyes of them both were opened, and they knew that they were naked; and they sewed fig leaves together, and made themselves aprons. And they heard the voice of the Lord God walking in the garden in the cool of the day: and Adam and his wife hid themselves from the presence of the Lord God amongst the trees of the garden, and the Lord God called unto Adam and said unto him, Where art thou? And he said, I heard they voice in the garden, and I was afraid, because I was naked; and I hid myself. And he said, Who told thee that thou was naked? Hast thou eaten of the tree, whereof I commanded thee that thou shouldest not eat?

Results of the fall. Rom. 3:23 For all have sinned; all fall short of God’s glorious standard. (NLT)
Here’s what happened in the fall. God crowned man with glory. Man sinned and fell short of that glory.
Hebrews 2:10 shows the circle of the glory. Man was crowned with glory and he fell from that glory. Through Jesus Christ [the anointed one and his anointing], man can return to the glory. Returning to that glory simply means receiving the gift of salvation.

Heb. 2:10 For it became him, for whom are all things, and by whom are all things, in bringing many sons unto glory, make the captain [author] of their salvation perfect through sufferings.

The predicament of the fall. To the right, high and lifted up, was the place of the throne of God. To the left low and very low stood satan with man cringing at his side. Between the place of God and the place of satan was a fixed gulf. God couldn’t reach down and take man up out of his predicament because he would have consumed him. Hebrews 12:29 says, “For our God is a consuming fire”. God consumes sin and with man in a fallen state of sin, he would have consumed him. This is what satan knew. To remove man would also have destroyed God’s word that man would have dominion over the works of my hands.

So, the precautions of the Old Testament show clearly why God did what he did. God’s glory stood behind a thick curtain in the Holy of Holies. The High Priest alone could enter there once a year on the Day of Atonement and when he did he took great precautions. It wasn’t that God did not want mankind in His presence; it was that man could not endure the glory of God. When the fall occurred in the garden it put man in a place that he could only re-enter into God’s presence as a High Priest.

1 Chr 13:3-14 And let us bring again the ark of our God to us… And all the congregation said that they would do so: for the thing was right in the eyes of all the people. So David gathered all Israel together … to bring the ark of God… And they carried the ark of God in a new cart out of the house of Abinadab: and Uzza and Ahio drave the cart. And when they came unto the threshing floor of Chidon, Uzza put forth his had to hold the ark: for the oxen stumble. And the anger of the LORD was kindled against Uzza, and he smote him, because he put his hand to the ark: and there he died before God. And David was displeased, because the LORD had make a breach upon Uzza … And David was afraid of God that day, saying, How shall I bring the ark of God home to me? So David brought not the ark home to himself to the city of David, but carried it aside into the house Obed-edom the Gittite. And the ark of God remained with the family of Obed-edom in his house three months. And the LORD blessed the house of Obed-edom, and all that he had.

Here we see that because of the fall man could not enter into God’s glory at any time except he was purified to do so. And that he had respect for the order of the things of God. His glory was lifted from man so Uzza touching the Ark of the Covenant was the same as Uzza touching God. And to touch God meant to touch his glory which man was not in any position to do without being consumed.

When the oxen stumbled, one of the men reached out to steady the ark and died. It wasn’t that God wanted to kill him it was that man could not withstand the glory of God. On one hand we see this happening and on the other we see when David sent the ark to Obed-edom the entire land was blessed. We witness the glory and the blessings. David didn’t understand that God’s glory was a consuming fire as well as an avenue to his blessings. Entering into his presence and touching the Ark of the Covenant was the same as being in his presence. In his presence was his glory and in his glory was his presence. When the fall of man occurred in the garden: that which allowed man to be in his glory was lifted.

The fall of man at this point, satan thought he had won. He thought he had succeeded in separating
God and man forever. But God had a plan. And that plan began in heaven before the foundation of the world. God did not need to do anything now. He already had done something.

The mystery of the Church. The New Testament calls God’s plan “mysteries”. The Companion Bible says: The English word “mystery” is a transliteration of the Greek word musterion, which means a scared secret --- something concealed that can be revealed. God concealed his plan for the church throughout the Old Testament. Prophets prophesied about it, while they wondered of what and whom they were speaking. Even the gospel writer’s didn’t grasp the meaning of the mystery. Until Paul comes along and God reveals what he had concealed, the mystery of the church.

The Holy Spirit through Paul refers to it as (Rom. 16:25) “…the mystery, which was kept secret since the world began”. Eph.3:9 “the mystery, which from the beginning of the world hath been hid in God…” Glory to God! What a hiding place!

1 Cor. 2:6-7 Howbeit we speak wisdom among them that are perfect; yet not the wisdom of this world, not of the princes of the world, that come to nought: But we speak the wisdom of God in a mystery, even the hidden wisdom, which God ordained before the world unto our glory.
When did God ordain the plan? Before the foundation of the world.
For what purpose? Unto our glory. Hallelujah!

1 Cor. 2:7 But rather what we are setting forth is a wisdom of God once hidden [from the human understanding] and now revealed to us by God; [that wisdom] which God devised and decreed before the ages for our glorification[that is, to lift us into the glory of His presence]. (The Amplified Bible)
1 Cor. 2:7-8 But we speak the wisdom of God in a mystery, even hidden wisdom, which God ordained before the world unto our glory. Which none of the princes of this world knew: for had they known it, they would not have crucified the Lord of glory.

If satan had seen the plan, he never would have lifted God’s spotless Lamb to the altar of the cross where His innocent blood could be shed to cleanse man to once again stand in the Glory of God. If satan had known that the crucifixion of Christ would have retuned man to his place of glory he never would have worked so hard to get Christ to the cross. Satan thought that to kill Christ Jesus was simply to get rid of him. Had he known that we would have the opportunity to be born again he would have let Christ live. But God had a plan that was a secret to all involved. Glory be to Jesus! The plan to save us from all unrighteousness, a plan to get us right back to the place in his glory from which we had fallen.
Here is what took place during the crucifixion. The Father of Glory (Eph. 1:17), sent the Lord of
Glory to lift up man who had been crowned with glory, but had fallen from that glory, back into the glory.
Rom. 11:36 “For him, and through him, and to him, are all things: to whom be glory forever. Amen.
Col. 1:26-27 “Even the mystery which hath been hid from ages and generations, but now is made manifest to his saints: To whom God would make known what is the riches of the glory of this mystery among the Gentiles; which is Christ in you, the hope of glory;”

Imagine satan’s dismay when the first man was “Born Again”. When he saw that the Anointed One, Jesus had come to take up resident inside man and to became his hope of glory he panicked. Man was born again in the glory of God. Man was back in the purpose of God’s original intent. That’s why the Bible refers to us as being born again. We are born back into the original intent of our being crown with the glory of God, made in their image and in their likeness.

In the last hours before he appears to receive the church, it will change into ever increasing splendor. It will change from one degree of glory to another, until there is only one more capstone of glory to be added to the temple. That will be the glorious rapture of the glorious church (Eph. 5:27).

Glory to God! That is what you and I are saved “to”. Salvation is not what we are saved “from” – the devil and sin. Salvation is what we are saved “to” – God and His Glory! His presence and His blessings.
Becoming a part of the glorious church. Don’t be ashamed of God’s preached word, because the preached word is the good news about Jesus. Within the gospel of Jesus Christ is the power of God. And this power is relinquish or given to all that believe. What power? The power to be saved. That’s the power we will receive if we believe. Also, the righteousness of God is revealed to us through the word and through the power of God. The more we grow in the word of God the easier it is to live a life of faith.

Rom. 1:16-17 For I am not ashamed of the gospel of Christ: for it is the power of God unto salvation to everyone that believeth; to the Jew first, and also to the Greek. For therein is the righteousness of God revealed from faith to faith: as it is written, The just shall live by faith.

What about sin in our lives? Everyone has sinned. Because of the fall in the garden man is born into sin or rather into a world that is sinful. God realizes this and has placed all of us into this category of having sinned. But we can’t stop there we must read farther to see that this state of sin has taken us away from the glory of God. In other words, we all are in a fallen state, a state that has uncovered us, or removed the glory of God from us. God’s main concern is that in that fallen state we no longer have the glory. In our efforts to recognize our sins don’t forget to see that God has also given us a way out of sin. When we were yet in sin Christ died for us. His death bought the gift of eternal life. You see, our lives can only have one ending and that is death. Someday all of us will die and yet we all have the opportunity to live forever. To do that we must be born again by accepting the free gift of salvation through Christ Jesus. Sin is sin and no one sin is greater than the other. God set the standards and we have missed them on occasion. But that does not push us out of the running we still have a chance if we choose it.

Rom. 3:23 For all have sinned, and come short of the glory of God.

Rom. 5: 6 For when we were yet without strength, in due time Christ died for the ungodly. For scarcely for righteous man will one die: yet peradventure for a good man some would even dare to die.

Rom. 6: 23 For the wages of sin is death; but the gift of God is eternal life through Jesus Christ our Lord.
Rom. 8:1-4 There is therefore now no condemnation to them which are in Christ Jesus, who walk not after the flesh, but after the Spirit. For the law of the Spirit of life in Christ Jesus hath made me free from the law of sin and death. For what the law would not do , in that it was weak through the flesh, God sending his own Son in the likeness of sinful flesh, and for sin, condemned sin in the flesh: That the righteousness of the law might be fulfilled in us, who walk not after the flesh, but after the Spirit.

The love of God toward us. God’s love is so strong toward us that he sent his own Son to die for us. The only way for God to restore us to his original intent was that Jesus die on the cross. Satan removed us from our rightful place in the glory of God and God wanted us back. So he did what he had to do and he did that because he loves us. That’s why no sin will ever keep the love of God from us. God doesn’t care about where we’ve been or what we’ve done, but he does care about where we’re going. That’s LOVE. There’s nothing in this world that can separate us from the love of God, absolutely nothing. We can’t even do anything to make God stop living us. God loves us when we don’t even love ourselves. Whatever sins we can name, whatever deeds we can think of that’s not enough to separate us from God’s love. Glory to God what a LOVE!

John 3:16 For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.

Rom. 8:31-35 What shall we then say to these things? If God be for us, who can be against us? He that spared not His own Son, but delivered Him up of us all, how shall He not with Him also freely given us all things? Who shall lay anything to the charge of God’s elect? It is God that justifieth. Who is he that condemneth? It is Christ that died, yea rather, that is risen again, who is even at the right hand of God, who also maketh intercession for us. Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or peril, or sword?

How to be saved. That was one of the questions Paul answered when he wrote to those in Rome. How we can be saved or born again is done according to the following scripture. Remember, this is the way God mapped out to get us back to our rightful place in his glory and to our covering of his glory.

Rom. 10:9-10 That if thou shalt confess with thy mouth the Lord Jesus, and shalt believe in thine heart that God hath raised him from the dead, thou shalt be saved. For with the heart man believeth unto righteousness; and with the mouth confession is made unto salvation.

Prayer for salvation. Heavenly Father, I come to you in the Name of Jesus. Your Word says, “…whosoever shall call on the Name of the Lord shall be saved” (Acts 2:21). I am calling on you. I pray and ask Jesus to come into my heart and be Lord over my life according to Roman 10:9-10. “That if thou shall confess with thy mouth the Lord Jesus and shalt believe in thine heart that God hath raised him from the dead, thou shalt be saved”. I confess that Jesus is Lord, and I believe in my heart that God raised him from the dead. I am now reborn! I am a Christian – a child of the Almighty God! I am saved! Glory to God I am a new creature in Christ Jesus!

We are new creations. Being a new creature or creation is us restored. We are no longer a sinful person bound for hell and a life of destruction. We are now bound for heaven and a life of abundance. Being a new creature means when God looks at us he can now see his glory on us once again. We are now covered in his glory with the ability to enter into his place of holiness. We are members of a family bound together by the love of God. Satan no longer has any rights to us because we belong to God and no one or nothing can cause a separation. Satan is angry and he can’t do anything about our new life. Glory be to Jesus!
2 Cor. 5:17 Therefore if any be in Christ, he is a new creature: old things are passed away; behold all things are become new.

So, walk in the fullness of the newness. Recognize that newness and that as far as God is concerned those old things have now become past. Our sins are washed away by the blood of Jesus. And now we have a new life a life where we can start over again with God and in God.

Rom. 12:1 I beseech you THEREFORE, brethren, by the mercies of God, that ye present your bodies a living sacrifice, holy, acceptable unto God, which is your reasonable service. And be not conformed to this world: but be ye transformed by the renewing of your mind, that ye may prove what is the good, an acceptable and perfect, will of God.

Starting over means we must make some efforts to walk in our new lives. We do this by offering our bodies to do the will of God. Meaning we study the word of God, pray and get involved in the things of God. This is very important. And that my friend is what we are saved to … a new glorious life filled with the blessings of God.

© 2003 Copyright Vernessa Walker Ministries
Provisions for the Redeemed Christian Center (aka Vernessa Walker Ministries)
P.O. Box 17424 Huntsville, Alabama 35810

Bibliography: Billye Brim Ministries. The Blood and The Glory. Tulsa, OK, 1995</string>
    <string name="header_5">Statement of Faith</string>
    <string name="paragraph_5">We believe that there is one God revealed in three persons; Father, Son and Holy Spirit, which is the creator of all things.

We believe that Jesus Christ is both divine and human. That he is of God and came in the flesh through virgin birth.

We believe in the bodily resurrection of Jesus Christ, that he was crucified, died, buried, resurrected, ascended to the Father, interceding for the saints and will return to rapture his church and judge the world.

We believe salvation is gained through repentance of sin by the grace of and the redemptive power of the blood of Jesus Christ.

We believe that believers should seek to exalt our Lord through sanctification, the Word and walking in holiness.

We believe that through the redemptive work we were given access to divine healing.

We believe in the water baptism and the baptism in the Holy Spirit with evidence of speaking in tongues, which is available to all believers, as well as the gifts of the Spirit.

We believe that all scripture, both Old and New Testament is the inspired Word of God.

</string>
    <string name="header_6">About The Ministry</string>
    <string name="paragraph_6">Provisions for the Redeemed Christian Center (aka Vernessa Walker Ministries) are a Word of God and Faith based ministry. We are open to all races. We are located in Huntsville, Alabama.</string>

</resources>
